Tufts Family Collection MS050
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Genealogical materials, circa 253 -- 350, 1817 -- 1992; MS050.002; 6.2 Linear Feet
  - Jay F. Tufts research files, circa 0253 -- 0350, 1817 -- 1982; MS050.002.001
    - Earley, Donald and Elgie Mae Earley - correspondence and photographs, circa 1951 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Donald Mansfield - correspondence, 1964 -- 1977; MS050.002.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Howard C. and Carlton Tufts - correspondence, 1962 -- 1977; MS050.002.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
    - Younck, Christine Tufts - correspondence, circa 1963 -- 1966; MS050.002.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and genealogies, circa 1955 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence, 1981; MS050.002.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
    - Andreason, Gertrude Elda Tufts; Howie Tufts; and Merton E. Tufts - correspondence, 1971 -- 1985; MS050.002.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Oscar Baker - photographs, genealogies, and correspondence, 1870 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
    - Seth Tufts Family - correspondence, 1957 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Albert and Karl Tufts - correspondence, 1953 -- 1959; MS050.002.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
    - Seigle, Lida Tufts - correspondence, 1955 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
    - Ertel, Emma Tufts - correspondence, 1955 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.003.00022 (Box 3)
    - Mider, Mabel Tufts - correspondence, 1956 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.003.00023 (Box 3)
    - Nicholson, Bessie Tufts - correspondence and genealogies, 1957 -- 1962; MS050.002.001.003.00024 (Box 3)
    - Livensparger Family - correspondence, 1963 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.003.00025 (Box 3)
    - Girton and Voelke families - correspondence, 1964 -- 1970; MS050.002.001.003.00026 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, John Quincy Adams - correspondence, circa 1955 -- 1980; MS050.002.001.003.00027 (Box 3)
    - Index and Genealogy of the Moses Tufts Family from 1799 to 1958, circa 1959 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.003.00028 (Box 3)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden and Kathleen W. Tuffs - postcards, 1959 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.003.00029 (Box 3)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden and Kathleen W. Tuffs - Christmas cards, 1957 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.003.00030 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Aaron, circa 1963; MS050.002.001.003.00031 (Box 3)
    - Rowland, Jay Warren and Kay (Katherine) Taylor Rowland - correspondence, 1964 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.003.00032 (Box 3)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden and Kathleen W. Tuffs - photographs and slides, circa 1958 -- 1975; MS050.002.001.003.00033 (Box 3)
    - Tofts, Tuffs, and Tufts family names - research and correspondence, circa 1957 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00034 (Box 3)
    - Clippings, 1960 -- 1974; MS050.002.001.003.00035 (Box 3)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden - clippings, circa 1962; MS050.002.001.003.00036 (Box 3)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden - Wansted Lake search, circa 1962; MS050.002.001.003.00037 (Box 3)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden - clippings, publications, and meeting agendas, 1957 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.003.00038 (Box 3)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden - drawings, maps, and sheet music, circa 1817 -- 1975; MS050.002.001.003.00039 (Box 3)
    - Woods family - correspondence, circa 1940 -- 1963; MS050.002.001.003.00040 (Box 3)
    - Farmington, Franklin County, Maine - publication, 1976; MS050.002.001.003.00041 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Jay and Ora Tufts - clippings and genealogies, 1960 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.003.00042 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, John Franklin - correspondence, 1879 -- 1954; MS050.002.001.003.00043 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, John William - genealogies, circa 1960; MS050.002.001.003.00044 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Eben - correspondence and clippings, 1867 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.003.00045 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Francis - photographs, circa 1955; MS050.002.001.003.00046 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, War G. - clippings and photographs, circa 1956 -- 1970; MS050.002.001.003.00047 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Bower Sunny - clippings, circa 1950; MS050.002.001.003.00048 (Box 3)
    - Maineville, Ohio - clippings, negatives, and photographs, circa 1900 -- 1910; MS050.002.001.003.00049 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Robert - photographs, circa 1980's; MS050.002.001.003.00050 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Joseph Francis Augustus photographs, circa 1860 -- 1870; MS050.002.001.003.00051 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Elbridge - photographs, circa 1900 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.003.00052 (Box 3)
    - Herrington, Pearl Hamilton - photographs and clippings, circa 1938 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.003.00053 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Stephen - photographs, circa 1890's; MS050.002.001.003.00054 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Jack Elsden - photographs, 1954 -- 1955; MS050.002.001.003.00055 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Richard - clippings, circa 1986; MS050.002.001.003.00056 (Box 3)
    - Albach, Clara Tufts - photographs, circa 1986 -- 1900; MS050.002.001.003.00057 (Box 3)
    - Jones, William Preble - photographs and clippings, circa 1954; MS050.002.001.003.00058 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, William Bernard - photographs, circa 1961; MS050.002.001.003.00059 (Box 3)
    - Wiese, Katherine Tufts - correspondence, circa 1964 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.003.00060 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, James K. and family - photographs, 1953; MS050.002.001.003.00061 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Edith Dean - portrait and photographs, circa 1900 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00062 (Box 3)
    - Wilson, Margaret Tufts - correspondence, 1960; MS050.002.001.003.00063 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Chester Warren - clippings, circa 1955 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.003.00064 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Stephen - genealogies, circa 1960; MS050.002.001.003.00065 (Box 3)
    - Henline, Mary G. Hamilton - correspondence, 1960 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.003.00066 (Box 3)
    - Hamilton, John Walter (Walt) - correspondence, 1960 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.003.00067 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, William Elmer and Hazel Delter - correspondence, 1958 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.003.00068 (Box 3)
    - Herrington, Pearl Hamilton - correspondence, 1956 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.003.00069 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Robert - genealogies, circa 1960; MS050.002.001.003.00070 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Robert Allen - correspondence, 1958; MS050.002.001.003.00071 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Harry W. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1958; MS050.002.001.003.00072 (Box 3)
    - Kokesh, Florence M. Tufts - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00073 (Box 3)
    - Creed, Elsie Alcock - correspondence, 1963 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.003.00074 (Box 3)
    - Stapley, Wallace C. - correspondence, 1963 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00075 (Box 3)
    - Eliott, Clarice R. - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00076 (Box 3)
    - Eliott, Edna Houser - correspondence, 1964 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.003.00077 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Donald E. - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00078 (Box 3)
    - Johnston, Velma Wiest - correspondence, 1965; MS050.002.001.003.00079 (Box 3)
    - King, Erman Alfred and Mary Alice King, circa 1955 - 1962; MS050.002.001.003.00080 (Box 3)
    - Kirk, Mollie Tufts - correspondence, circa 1957 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.003.00081 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, William Bernard - genealogies, circa 1982; MS050.002.001.003.00082 (Box 3)
    - Tufts families of New Orleans, Mobile, Nicksborg, and Waveland Mississippi - correspondence, circa 1952 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00083 (Box 3)
    - Carton, Anne Lou Tufts - correspondence, circa 1957; MS050.002.001.003.00084 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Sharon - correspondence, 1965 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.003.00085 (Box 3)
    - Adams family - clippings, 1975; MS050.002.001.003.00086 (Box 3)
    - Gerndt, Ruby DaFore Tufts - correspondence and photographs, circa 1960 -- 1976; MS050.002.001.003.00087 (Box 3)
    - Wormald, Elsie - correspondence, 1956 -- 1958; MS050.002.001.003.00088 (Box 3)
    - Walsh, Muriel - correspondence, 1968; MS050.002.001.003.00089 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Bowen and Octavia Tufts - clippings, circa 1950 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.003.00090 (Box 3)
    - Wills Family - correspondence, 1958; MS050.002.001.003.00091 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Moses - family history and genealogies, circa 1958; MS050.002.001.003.00092 (Box 3)
    - Carlson, Maye - correspondence, 1952 -- 1959; MS050.002.001.003.00093 (Box 3)
    - Wildasin, Henry - correspondence and clippings, 1954 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.003.00094 (Box 3)
    - Tuft, Warren Porter - correspondence, 1954; MS050.002.001.003.00095 (Box 3)
    - Tufts, Samuel R. - correspondence, 1955 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.003.00096 (Box 3)
    - Shepley, Hayden Richardson - correspondence, 1967 -- 1968; MS050.002.001.003.00097 (Box 3)
    - Richards, Mabel B. - correspondence, 1972 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.003.00098 (Box 3)
    - Ward, Olive May Malish - correspondence, 1956 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.003.00099 (Box 3)
    - Dwinell, Elaine M. (Walters) and Merril L. Dwinell - correspondence, 1957 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.003.00100 (Box 3)
    - Waring, John M. and Dorthy Hague Waring - correspondence, 1955 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.003.00101 (Box 3)
    - Smith, Clarice Tufts - correspondence, 1965 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.003.00102 (Box 3)
    - Cobb, Rosalie Margaret Karapetoff - scrapbook, 1919 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
    - Driver, Edith Doane - scrapbook, 1930 -- 1980; MS050.002.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
    - Tufts, Oliver B. - correspondence and photographs, 1945 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden and Kathleen (Kay) Wood Tuffs - correspondence, 1955 -- 1978; MS050.002.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden and Kathleen (Kay) Wood Tuffs - genealogies, circa 1982; MS050.002.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
    - Mills, Flora Pearson - correspondence, 1943 -- 1958; MS050.002.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Paul Hartley - correspondence, 1954 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
    - Hancock, Sidney Tufts - correspondence, circa 1949 -- 1959; MS050.002.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Thomas Clark Sr. - correspondence and family tree, 1957 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, William Kingsland - correspondence, photographs, and family tree, 1962 -- 1978; MS050.002.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Horance A. and Helen Burns Tufts - correspondence, 1951 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Kingsley - correspondence, circa 1953 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, James Arthur III - correspondence, circa 1963 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
    - England - correspondence, 1953 -- 1967; MS050.002.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
    - Price, Lola Amy Tufts - correspondence and genealogies, circa 1954 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Josiah Jr. and Maude Tufts Harris - correspondence and genealogies, circa 1954 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Josiah Jr. and Mary L. Tufts Pierson - correspondence and genealogies, circa 1954 -- 1970; MS050.002.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Herbert William - correspondence, circa 1955 -- 1975; MS050.002.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
    - Glover, Mildred Potter - correspondence, circa 1961 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Ann and Eulilia Tufts Mitchell - correspondence, 1955 -- 1966; MS050.002.001.005.00018 (Box 5)
    - Hyer, Richard - correspondence, 1963 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.005.00019 (Box 5)
    - Houlette, Alta Tufts - correspondence, 1953 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.005.00020 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Karl Herrington - correspondence, 1955; MS050.002.001.005.00021 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Gordon Roy - correspondence and clippings, 1957 -- 1968; MS050.002.001.005.00022 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Arthur Gordon - correspondence, circa 1955 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.005.00023 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Winfield - records, 1875 -- 1966; MS050.002.001.005.00024 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Jay F. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1983; MS050.002.001.005.00025 (Box 5)
    - Tufts University - correspondence, circa 1953 -- 1960; MS050.002.001.005.00026 (Box 5)
    - Grant, Peter - correspondence, 1961; MS050.002.001.005.00027 (Box 5)
    - Tufts University - correspondence, 1956 -- 1977; MS050.002.001.005.00028 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, John - correspondence, circa 1956 -- 1963; MS050.002.001.005.00029 (Box 5)
    - McMaichael, Julia M. - correspondence, 1956; MS050.002.001.005.00030 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Frank H. - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00031 (Box 5)
    - Adams, Etta Alberta Tufts - correspondence, 1954 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.005.00032 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Thelma Wood and Mary Ruth (Tufts) Peeler - correspondence, 1957 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.005.00033 (Box 5)
    - Cosgrove, Ruth Tufts - correspondence, 1939 -- 1973; MS050.002.001.005.00034 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Aaron - correspondence, 1952 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.005.00035 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, A. W. - correspondence, 1954; MS050.002.001.005.00036 (Box 5)
    - Clift, Lula - correspondence, 1955 -- 1959; MS050.002.001.005.00037 (Box 5)
    - Churchill, Mary Church - correspondence, 1967 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.005.00038 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Eveden Garnet - correspondence, circa 1935 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00039 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, William Mann - correspondence, 1955 -- 1963; MS050.002.001.005.00040 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Arthur E. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.005.00041 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Ralph W. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.005.00042 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, John S. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.005.00043 (Box 5)
    - New data received after book date, 1955 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00044 (Box 5)
    - Barham, Bertha Lou Tufts - correspondence, 1953 -- 1959; MS050.002.001.005.00045 (Box 5)
    - Babcock, Hazel and Roy Babcock - correspondence, 1956 -- 1968; MS050.002.001.005.00046 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Anne B. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.005.00047 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, A. Courtney - correspondence, 1954 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.005.00048 (Box 5)
    - Calnan, Mary Tufts - correspondence, 1965; MS050.002.001.005.00049 (Box 5)
    - Ayer, Josephine Stevens - correspondence, 1944 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00050 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Wanda L. - clippings, 1971; MS050.002.001.005.00051 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, M. Clarence - clippings, circa 1956 -- 1970; MS050.002.001.005.00052 (Box 5)
    - Tufts University - correspondence and clippings, circa 1950 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.005.00053 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Paula P. - correspondence, 1955 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.005.00054 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, C. Albert - correspondence, clippings, and publications, 1918 -- 1968; MS050.002.001.005.00055 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, G. Eldon - records, 1958 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00056 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Annie Hellen - correspondence, 1955 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.005.00057 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Edgar S. - correspondence, 1957 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00058 (Box 5)
    - Goodoien, Carol M. - correspondence, 1968 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.005.00059 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Frank A. - correspondence, 1954; MS050.002.001.005.00060 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Elizabeth Trances - correspondence, 1954 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00061 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Edith Maria Goodspeed - correspondence and clippings, circa 1894 -- 1981; MS050.002.001.005.00062 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Jeanni Wilcox - correspondence and clippings, circa 1953 -- 1975; MS050.002.001.005.00063 (Box 5)
    - Denmark and Holland research- correspondence, 1953 -- 1955; MS050.002.001.005.00064 (Box 5)
    - D.A.R. - correspondence, 1963 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.005.00065 (Box 5)
    - Dickore, Marie - correspondence, 1954 -- 1963; MS050.002.001.005.00066 (Box 5)
    - Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints - correspondence, 1949 -- 1963; MS050.002.001.005.00067 (Box 5)
    - The old Peter Tufts house - clippings, 1966; MS050.002.001.005.00068 (Box 5)
    - Barragy, Terrence J. - correspondence, 1969 -- 1971; MS050.002.001.005.00069 (Box 5)
    - Griesco, Janet and William H. Darr - correspondence, 1959 -- 1962; MS050.002.001.005.00070 (Box 5)
    - Giffin, Edythe - correspondence, 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00071 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Glenn D. - correspondence, 1954 -- 1961; MS050.002.001.005.00072 (Box 5)
    - Bedell, Henry B. - correspondence, 1971; MS050.002.001.005.00073 (Box 5)
    - Hill, Coraline Tufts - correspondence, 1954 -- 1958; MS050.002.001.005.00074 (Box 5)
    - Bennett, Betsy B. - correspondence, 1963 -- 1965; MS050.002.001.005.00075 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Rachael Alberta - correspondence, circa 1954 -- 1964; MS050.002.001.005.00076 (Box 5)
    - Haines, Priscilla - correspondence and genealogies, 1965 -- 1966; MS050.002.001.005.00077 (Box 5)
    - Beal, Loura A. - correspondence, 1953 -- 1955; MS050.002.001.005.00078 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Percy Harrington - correspondence, 1954; MS050.002.001.005.00079 (Box 5)
    - American Heritage - correspondence, 1957; MS050.002.001.005.00080 (Box 5)
    - Hartman, J. Crawford - correspondence, 1955 -- 1956; MS050.002.001.005.00081 (Box 5)
    - Hervey, Wade S. - correspondence, 1952 -- 1957; MS050.002.001.005.00082 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Martha M. - correspondence, 1960; MS050.002.001.005.00083 (Box 5)
    - Neal, Margaret Tufts and Eugenia Stinson Tufts - correspondence, 1955 -- 1969; MS050.002.001.005.00084 (Box 5)
    - Tufts, Jay F. - correspondence and research organizational chart, 1980 -- 1982; MS050.002.001.005.00085 (Box 5)
    - Tuffs, Jack Elsden - Roman brick and tile pieces, circa 0253 -- 0350; MS050.002.001.006.00001 (Box 6, Object 1-7)
    - Burns, Ida - Bible, 1865 -- 1866; MS050.002.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
    - Smith, Lilla May Tufts - daguerreotypes of Gardiner Tufts and Nancy Tufts, 1851; MS050.002.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
    - Bush, Dean - slides, circa 1958; MS050.002.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
    - Brittan, Pearl Tufts - will, 1951; MS050.002.001.008.00005 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Moran, Mary Estelle Tufts, 1953 -- 1972; MS050.002.001.008.00006 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Tufts Kinsmen, 1975 -- 1992; MS050.002.002
    This sub-series consists of the Tufts Kinsmen newsletters and correspondence dating from 1975 to 1992. The Tufts Kinsmen newsletters were published quarterly by the Tufts Kinsmen Association circa 1974 to circa 1992, and featured Tufts family stories, histories, and genealogies. This sub-series contains an almost complete run of the newsletter. The Tufts Kinsmen Association was founded by Herbert F. Adams in 1974 as a result of his Tufts Kinsmen Project, Adams' research into Tufts family genealogy. The Association was incorporated in the mid-1980s with David D. Tufts as its President; J. Arthur Tufts as its Vice President; Donald M. Tufts, William True, and Susan Tufts as its the Board of Directors; and Herbert F. Adams as the Family Historian.
    This sub-series includes Tufts Kinsmen correspondence and photographs in addition to the newsletters. Correspondence is mainly between Adams, the Tufts Kinsmen Association, and the Tufts archives, between 1970-1993. Topics include the newsletter, Tufts family reunions at Tufts University in 1980 and 1983, and Adams' research for the second edition of his book Tufts Kinsmen (published 2010). There is also correspondence discussing the creation of a Tufts Kinsmen Scholarship at Tufts University.
    - Tufts Kinsmen, 1992; MS050.002.002.004.003 (Box 3)
    - Tufts Kinsmen Scholarship - correspondence and newsletters, circa 1979 -- 1993; MS050.002.002.005.00086 (Box 5)
    - Tufts Kinsmen - photographs and newsletters, circa 1975 -- 1982; MS050.002.002.005.00087; 2 Folder(s) (Box 5)
    - Tufts Kinsmen - newsletters, circa 1980 -- 1992; MS050.002.002.005.00088 (Box 5)
  - Tufts family Bible, 1843; MS050.002.007.00003 (Box 7)
    This family Bible, dated 1843, originally belonged to Susan Adams Tufts, who died in 1860.It contains a family tree recording eight generations related to Susan Adams Tufts and her husband Peter Tufts (died 1859).
- Legal and financial records, 1791 -- 2009; MS050.003; .9 Linear Feet
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  The majority of the legal and financial records were purchased by in Tufts University acquisitions department as a group from The Manuscripts Company of Springfield, Virginia in 1978. The deed and accompanying correspondence in folder MS050.003.008.00003 were donated by Leonard Carmichael in November 1949. The materials in folder MS050.003.008.00004 were a gift of Mrs. Donald Howard, August 1971.
  This series contains business ledgers, account books, cash receipts, correspondence, deeds, and wills of several members of the Tufts family of Charlestown, Massachusetts, dating mainly from 1797 to 1860. The majority of these records document the business activities of the Tufts family brickworks and tannery in Charlestown, Massachusetts.
  The Tufts family of Charlestown (later Somerville), Massachusetts, owned an extensive brickworks and tannery in the early nineteenth century. The family business was founded by Daniel Tufts (1753 – 1838), a farmer and descendant of the Peter Tufts who settled in Charlestown in the 1600s. He established the industries that, along with land, would later form the basis of his sons' considerable estates. The series includes the business records of Daniel Tufts and his sons Daniel Tufts (1776 – 1868), Charles Tufts (1781 – 1876), and Nathaniel Tufts (1786 – 1872). The majority of the records appear in the hand of Daniel Tufts II, the eldest son, who appears very early in the accounts as a partner of his father.
  Custodial History
  Materials acquired from the The Manuscript Company of Springfield were originally purchased by them from a fellow vendor, unnamed, who "had them for several years" and had acquired them from yet a third vendor, also unnamed.
  - Cash accounts, 1823 -- 1854; MS050.003.007.00005 (Box 7)
    Description from dealer: Cash account book, folio, 1/4 leather, boards. 178pp. accounts (completely filled). Fine clerical hand. Exterior heavily worn, dampstaining near covers. Sixteen years of cash-accounts, 1823-1839. Wages paid, raw materials purchased, sales. Also a few notations of laborers and schedules of notes payable and due, to 1852.
  - Ledger, 1797 -- 1816; MS050.003.007.00006 (Box 7)
    Description from dealer: Ledger-book, narrow folio. 174pp. accounts (completely filled). Uncovered boards, no backstrip. Binding loose, but still sewn. Waterstaining throughout. Laid paper. Entitled "The ledger Daniel Tufts, Jun. His Book Charlestown, Nov. 11, 1801." This is the record of the family business in leather and bricks. Includes labor, purchase of raw materials, bricks, leather, provision, board, etc. The volume also contains accounts for many members of the Tufts family, including Daniel Sr., Daniel Jr., Gilbert, Nathaniel, Amos, Timothy, Benjamin. A number of the accounts are for large sales of brick, over 200,000 (largest noted 356,000), as well as large purchases and sales of hides and leather. The workers were charged for their training and lost time to illness, travel, etc. The labor accounts show that the Tufts generally procured the clay for their brickworks from their own land.
  - Tannery daybook, 1833 -- 1856; MS050.003.007.00007 (Box 7)
    Daybook, folio, 134pp. accounts (nearly filled), entitled "Daniel Tufts Jun. Day Book Charlesto,tn April 24, 1833." Very heavily worn, covers detached, dampstained throughout. Neat clerical hand. Interior fine. Twenty-three years of continuous accounts, 1833-1856, for leather sales, hides, horns, cattle tails, hair, etc.
  - Cash accounts, 1811 -- 1823; MS050.003.007.00008 (Box 7)
    Description from dealer: Cash account. book, folio, 1/4 leather, boards. Worn, but intact. Covers and binding secure. 174pp. of accounts (completely filled) in neat, clerical hand, covering twelve continuous years of cash accounts, 1811-1823. Plus a summary of individual laborers' tenure. The cash accounts of the business, containing the records of goods purchased and sold; wages; etc.
  - Brickyard and tannery journal, 1817 -- 1850; MS050.003.007.00009 (Box 7)